Joshua K. Augsburger

(567) 208-6305 | joshua.augsburger08@gmail.com jaugsbu2.github.io/portfolio-react www.linkedin.com/in/josh-augsburger

Professional Profile

An Engineering Manager with a passion for continuous learning and a knack for producing captivating products and applications that move businesses forward. Master's degree in mechanical engineering with diverse product development background, and current web development bootcamp student. Experienced in start to finish project management, from defining design requirements and vision to full scale production. Expertise as the leader or member of the cross-functional development team, working remotely or onsite.

Skills and Tools

- JavaScript
- HTML/CSS
- React
- Bootstrap
- NodeJS

- Express
- MySQL
- MongoDB
- Mongoose

- SolidWorks
- Design for Manufacturability
- Design for Six Sigma
- Project Management
- Collaborative Design

Work Experience

Smart Bar USA Denver, CO

Engineering Manager

1/2017 - Present

- Core member of the management team that brought the business operating profit from a \$600K annual loss to a >\$500K annual profit this year, without significant shareholder funding.
- Planned and executed a cocktail dispenser that doubled the ingredient capacity of the original product offering, bringing the business its first year of profitability the year after product launch.
- Scoped, developed, and launched the first-to-market automated cocktail dispenser system for front bar applications, creating a 100% increase in total sales volume the year after launch.
- Provide a competitive edge by designing and launching a patented pouring nozzle that provides a 30% increase in soda carbonation over the previous nozzle.

GE Appliances Louisville, KY

Mechanical Design Engineer

7/2016 - 1/2017

- Implemented various cost out projects resulting in over \$500,000 of annual cost savings.
- Developed a "silent" articulating mullion concept for GE French Door Refrigerators that would allow the refrigerator to better compete in the market and reduce energy usage by about 1%.
- Designed and proved feasibility of a low-cost refrigerator door closing mechanism that would result in \$1.25 million in annual savings. This design was later patented.

Edison Engineering Development Rotation Program Engineer

7/2013 - 1/2016

Member of various engineering teams within the product design and production engineering division
of GE Appliances organization. This consisted of four 6-month rotations, and one year long rotation.
Highlights: Develop 8 refrigerator components, >\$1.2M dishwasher cost out, Eliminate top scrap issue.

Education

UC Berkely Extension – Software Engineering Bootcamp	4/2023
University of Louisville – Master of Science Mechanical Engineering - Structural Appliance Design	5/2016
University of Toledo – Bachelor of Science Mechanical Engineering	5/2013

Trainings and Certificates

- US Patent #9739523, #2022192765
- GE Frontline Leadership Training
- GE Appliances Design Engineering Internship 4 Undergraduate Semesters